Guide to the Daily Worker and Daily World Cartoon Collection GRAPHICS.024.001
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series II: Subject Cartoons, 1937-2000
  - Subseries B: General Subject Cartoons, 1947-2000
    - Bulgaria, 1980s (Box 3A, Folder 8)
    - Bush, George H.W., 1988-1993 (Box 3A, Folder 8)
    - Bush, Neil, 1990 (Box 3A, Folder 9)
    - Business Structure, 1982-1998 (Box 3A, Folder 10)
    - Capitalism, 1994 (Box 3A, Folder 11)
    - Casey, Bill, 1983 (Box 3A, Folder 12)
    - Censorship, 1949-1985 (Box 3A, Folder 13)
    - Central America, 1981-1999 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Children, 1980, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Chile, 1973-1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Christmas, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - C.I.A., 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Circus, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Class Struggle, 1947, 1970-1997 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Clinton, Bill, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Cold War, 1989, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Communism, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Communist Party USA, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Congress, 1973-1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Contras, 1986, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Contract Negotiations, 1979-1996 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Corporate Salanes, 1987-1996 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Corruption I, 1979-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Corruption II, 1979-1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Communism, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Cuba, 1980-2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - C.W.A., 1986 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Defense Spending, 1981-1991 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Deficit, 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Demonstrations, undated (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Disabilities, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Disarmament, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Dolan, John T., undated (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Downsizing, 1980-1999 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Draft, 1981, undated (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Drooker, Eric (artist), undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Drugs, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - Economy, 1981-1997 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - Education, 1978-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - Elections: 1988 (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - Elections: 1996 (Box 4, Folder 33)
    - Environment, 1985-1996 (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - Equality: Racism, 1949- 1996 (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Equality: Sexism, 1982-1995, undated (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Exxon, 1979-1991, undated (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Farmers, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - FBI, undated (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Flag Burning, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
    - Foreign Countries, 1981-1997 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    - Foreign Language Cartoons I, 1980-1993 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    - Foreign Language Cartoons II, 1980-1993 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    - Foreign Language Cartoons III, 1980-1993 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    - Foreign Policy, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Forrestal, James, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - France, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Free Trade, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Freedom of Information, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Freedom of Information, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    - Gags, 1970-1995 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - General Motors, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    - General System, 1973-1999 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    - Gingrich, Newt, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 53)
    - Goetz, Bernhard, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Grenada, 1981-1986 (Box 4, Folder 55)
    - Gulf War, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Haiti, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 57)
    - Hasenfus, Eugene, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 58)
    - Hatch Act, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 59)
    - Healthcare, 1981-1997 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    - Homeless, 1987, undated (Box 4, Folder 61)
    - Housing, 1948-1996 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    - H.U.D., 1990 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    - Human Rights, 1969-1995 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    - Immigration, 1987-1994 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    - Imperialism, 1970-1997 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - INF Pact, 1993, undated (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - Joseph, S. (artist), undated (Box 4, Folder 68)
    - Justice System, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    - Kissinger, Henry, 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 70)
    - Koch, Edward, 1982, undated (Box 4, Folder 71)
    - Konupacki, Huck (artist), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    - Labor, 1986-1992 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - Labor Day, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 74)
    - Lumber Industry, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 75)
    - Marcos, Ferdinand, 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 76)
    - May Day, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Media, 1969-1999 (Box 4, Folder 78)
    - Meese, Edwin, 1984-1988 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Mideast, 1982-1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 80)
    - Miners, undated (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - Minimum Wage, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 82)
    - Moral Majority, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 83)
    - NAFTA, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 84)
    - Nicaragua, 1983-1989 (Box 4, Folder 85)
    - Nixon, R., 1970-1994, undated (Box 4, Folder 86)
    - North, Ollie, 1988-1994 (Box 4, Folder 87)
    - Nuclear, 1979-1994 (Box 4, Folder 88)
    - Oil/Gas, 1977-1981 (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - Organizing, 1948-1995 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Payne, Gene, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Peace, undated (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - "People Before Profits", undated (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Perot, Ross, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Personalities, 1959-1995 (Box 4, Folder 95)
    - Poland, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Police, 1968-1995 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Poverty, 1989-1997 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Presidency, undated (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Prisons, 1978-1997 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Privatizing, 1993-1996 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Quayle, undated (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Reagan, Ronald, 1981-1994 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Rehnquist, William, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Republicans, 1987-1994, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Rich and Filthy Rich, 1982-1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Right Wing, 1949-1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Rollins, Ed, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Russia, 1987-1995, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - S and L, 1990-1991 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Safety and Health, 1979-1995 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - S.D.I., 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Sharon, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Simpson-Mazzoli Immigration Act, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Simpson, O.J., undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Social Security, 1988-1998 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Souter, David, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - South Africa, 1980-1990 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Space Program, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Sports, 1980-1992 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Star Wars, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Stevens, Ted (?), 1978 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Strikes, 1975-1990 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Summit, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Supreme Court, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Swaggart, Jimmy, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Sweatshops, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Taxes, 1979-1996 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Television, 1982, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Tower, John, undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Trade, 1992-1994 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Trade Union Committee, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Transnationals, 1979-1996 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Transportation, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Trident, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Trump, Donald, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Unemployment, 1979-1996 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Unions, 1989-1993 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - United Auto Workers, circa 1977 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Veterans, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Voting, 1980-1995 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Wage Freeze I, 1971-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Wage Freeze II, 1971-1973, undated (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Watt, James, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Welfare, 1987-1997 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Weinberger, Caspar, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - WFTU Congress, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - Whalen, Eileen (artist), 1979, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Winston, Henry, undated (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - Women Workers, undated (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Workers' Rights, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 48)
- Series III: Cartoons by Artist, 1928-2002
  Series III: Cartoons by Artist consists of cartoons produced by artists, including: Fred Ellis, James Erickson, Norman Goldberg, Ollie Harrington, Hal Kinkaid, and Robert Minor, among various others. Each of the above artists' materials are arranged into separate subseries, with a general run subseries of other artists following. The cartoons in this series, are, for the most part original and signed.
  - Subseries A: Fred Ellis, 1928-1950s
    Fred Ellis was a staff artist for the Daily Worker/Daily world/ He has hundreds of original cartoons and sketches in this subseries. Most of the cartoons and sketches are undated, however likely it dates from the 1940s and 1950s. Each original drawing or sketch is usually produced with a waxy crayon on paper. Also by Fred Ellis are a number of scrapbooks of his works as reproduced in the Daily Worker/Daily World. The scrapbooks range in date from 1936-1941. Ellis' work covers a dynamic range of subjects often portraying the plight of labor against big business as depicted by two central figures, a large "Big Business" man in suit and tie and a burly laborer, usually in overalls or with a miner's hat. The sketches here trace the major events of the time, including presidential elections, McCarthyism, and fights for civil liberties.
    - Cartoons (copies), 1928-1930 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1941 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1942 (Box 5, Folder 55)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1942 (Box 5, Folder 56)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1944-1947 (Box 5, Folder 57)
    - Cartoons (newsprint), 1938-1948 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    - Cartoons (newsprint, with Gropper), 1936-1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons (originals) I, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons (originals) II, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Cartoons (originals) III, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons (originals) IV, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons (originals) V, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons (originals) VI, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons (originals) VII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Cartoons (originals) VIII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Cartoons (originals) IX, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons (originals) X, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Cartoons (originals) XI, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Cartoons (originals) XII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Cartoons (originals) XIII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Cartoons (originals) XIV, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Cartoons (originals) XV, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Cartoons (originals) XVI, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Cartoons (originals) XVII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Cartoons (originals) XVIII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Cartoons (originals) XIX, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Cartoons (originals) XX, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXI, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXIII, 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Cartoons (originals) I, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons (originals) II, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Cartoons (originals) III, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons (originals) IV, undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons (originals) V, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons (originals) VI, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons (originals) VII, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Cartoons (originals) VIII, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Cartoons (originals) IX, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons (originals) X, undated (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Cartoons (originals) XI, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons (originals) XII, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Cartoons (originals) XIII, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons (originals) XIV, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons (originals) XV, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons (originals) XVI, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons (originals) XVII, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Cartoons (originals) XVIII, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Cartoons (originals) XIX, undated (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons (originals) XX, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXI, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXII, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXIII, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXIV, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXV, undated (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXVI, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXVII, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXVIII, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXIX, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXX, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXXI, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXXII, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Cartoons (originals) XXXIII, undated (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Notebook, circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 59)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1936 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 61)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1937 (Box 5, Folder 62)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1938 (Box 5, Folder 63)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1939 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1940 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Scrapbook: Daily Worker Cartoons (newsprint), 1941 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Sketches (not printed), undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Eric (James Erickson), 1954-1974
    In this subseries are the original cartoons of James Erickson, who signs his work Eric. His works are ink on board and depict Wall St., China and Mao Tse-Tung, labor struggles, and peace. The cartoons are dated 1954-1974.
    - Cartoons (originals) I, 1954-1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Cartoons (originals) II, 1954-1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Cartoons (originals) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Cartoons (originals) II, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Cartoons (originals) III, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Cartoons (originals) IV, undated (Box 8, Folder 4a)
  - Subseries C: Norman Goldberg, 1993
    This subseries contains the cartoons of Norman Goldberg. There are copies as well as pre-press prints. The cartoons range in date from the 1980s-1990s. In his distinctive style, Goldberg's cartoons often mock boardrooms full of company executives and are strongly anti-corporate. He also pokes fun at President's Reagan and Bush, as well as Vice President Dan Quayle.
    - Cartoons (copies) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Cartoons (copies) II, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Cartoons (copies) III, undated (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Cartoons (copies) IV, undated (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Cartoons (pre-press), circa 1993, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons (pre-press) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Cartoons (pre-press) II, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Subseries D: Ollie Harrington, 1950-1987
    The Harrington cartoons in this subseries range in date from 1950-1987. They cover a number of different topics, but in particular focus on international affairs and criticizing US Presidents, including: Richard Nixon, Gerald Ford, and Jimmy Carter. Rats feature prominently in Harrington's work, often used to show corruption and injustice. The cartoons are pre-press originals, some were printed while others were not used. There is also a large portion of the cartoons that are newsprint reproductions of cartoons as printed in the Daily Worker.
    - Biographical Articles, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Biographical Articles, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1960s (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1976, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Cartoons (copies), 1970s (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Cartoons (copies), undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Cartoons (newsprint), 1950s (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Cartoons (newsprint), 1960s (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Cartoons (newsprint) I, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - Cartoons (newsprint) II, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - Cartoons (newsprint) III, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Cartoons (newsprint) IV, 1970s (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Cartoons (newsprint), 1971-1977 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons (newsprint), 1980s (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Cartoons (newsprint), undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1960-1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1968 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Jun 1969-Aug 1969 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Sep 1969-Dec 1969 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Feb 1970-Jun 1970 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Sep 1970 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Oct 1970-Dec 1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Mar 1971-Apr 1971 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Jul 1971-Aug 1971 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), Sep 1971-Dec 1971 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1971 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1972 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press) I, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press) II, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press) I, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press) II, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1975 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1976-1979 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press), 1987, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press) I, undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press) II, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Cartoons (originals/ pre-press) III, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Cartoons (photocopies), undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Subseries E: Hal Kincaid, 1968
    The cartoons in this subseries are from Hal Kinkaid. All are original. A few are dated 1968, but for the most part are undated. The cartoons represent prominent political and military figures: Eugene Dennis, Joseph McCarthy, and General Douglas McArthur. Topically the cartoons depict struggles for civil liberties and peace as well as big business, congress, the House Un-American Activities Committee, and the military.
    - Cartoons (originals), 1968, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Cartoons (originals) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - Cartoons (originals) II, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Subseries F: Robert Minor, 1930s-2002
    Robert Minor was a prominent Communist Party of the United States of America leader and writer. He also contributed cartoons to the Daily Worker/Daily World. In this subseries are several copies of his cartoons as well as an exhibit catalog from the Cornelia Cotton Gallery, which featured cartoons by Minor as well as his wife, Lydia Gibson. There are also a number of original sketches and notes as well as a small watercolor sketchbook in this subseries. The material ranges in date from the 1930s-2002.
    - Cartoons (copies), undated (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - Cornelia Cotton Gallery (with Lydia Gibson), 2002 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Sketchbook, circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - Sketches and Notes, 1953, undated (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Subseries G: Other Artists, 1931-1995
    This subseries contains both copied and original cartoons from a number of artists. The material ranges in date from 1931-1995. Artists with significant material in this subseries include: Augie, Seymour Joseph, and Bernard Kassoy. The latter has cartoons dealing primarily with New York teachers and witch hunts. Also found in this series are copies of cartoons by Gropper, Hugo Gellert (as well as a signature from him), Art Young, and a signed sketch from Pete Seeger.
    - Andrews, Bill (copies), 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Augie (originals), 1942, undated (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Augie (originals) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Augie (originals) II, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Augie (originals) III, undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Avrom (originals), 1974, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Avrom (originals), 1974 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Blashko, A (copies), undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Bloom (originals), undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Burck, Jacob (newsprint), undated (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correl, Richard (newsprint), undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Darcy, Sam (copies), undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Drake, Ron (originals), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Evergood, Philip (article), 1947 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Gellert, Hugo (copies) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Gellert, Hugo (copies) II, undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Gellert, Hugo (copies) III, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Gellert, Hugo (newsprint), 1931 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Gellert, Hugo (signature), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Gosta (original), undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Gottlieb, Harry: Portraits of Fred Ellis (originals), 1963-1965 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Gropper, William (newsprint), 1939-1940, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Hale (originals), undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Harman, Fred (copies), 1941 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Hill, Sam (originals), undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - Huck/ Konopacki (copies), 1987-1995 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Huck/ Konopacki (copies), undated (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - Johnson, Jack (originals), undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Joseph, Seymour (copies), 1972-1990 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Joseph, Seymour (copies), 1987 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Joseph, Seymour (copies) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - Joseph, Seymour (copies) II, undated (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Joseph, Seymour (originals), 1964, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Joseph, Seymour (originals), 1964-1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Joseph, Seymour (originals), 1988-1989, undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Kassoy (teachers/ education/ witch hunts) (originals) I, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Kassoy (teachers/ education/ witch hunts) (originals) II, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Keller, Charles (copies), 1947, 1980-1987, undated (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Keller, Charles (originals), 1939, undated (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Kerkam (originals), undated (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - Lipschutz, Peggy (originals), 1979, undated (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - Meen, Joe (originals), 1963 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - Lefty/ L (originals), 1953, undated (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Reisman, Phil (originals), undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Rosenthal, Frances (originals), undated (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Rosenthal, Seymour (originals), undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Seckar, Alvena (original artwork), undated (Box 6, Folder 61a)
    - Seeger, Pete (sketch, signed), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - Sequeiros, David Alfaro (newsprint), 1934 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Sherman, Alfred (copies), 1967 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Van Veen, Sadie (originals), undated (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - Various Artists, 1949-1990, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Wright, Fred (copies), undated (Box 6, Folder 64)
    - Wright, Fred (originals), circa 1960-1966, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
    - Young, Art (copies) I, undated (Box 6, Folder 66)
    - Young, Art (copies) II, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Series IV: Ephemera and other Graphics, 1953-1992